American Philosophical Society Archives. Record Group IId. 1837-1844 APS.Archives.IId APS.Archives.IId
American Philosophical Society
- Papers
  - Letter to the American Philosophical Society, May 29, 1843; 7 7/8" x 7 1/4"; English, John B.
    Philadelphia, 1 p. and endorsement. A.L.S. Invitation to attend discourse to be given in memory of Thomas Godfrey, by Dr. G[ouverneur] Emerson, at Laurel Hill cemetery.
  - Measurements of the foetal cranium., May 29, 1843; 7 7/8" x 12 5/8"; Meigs, Charles D. (Charles Delucena), 1792-1869
    4 pp. and endorsement. Com. Read by the author at the centenary celebration of 1843. See Pro., III, 127-129.
  - Summary of a series of observations on Egyptian ethnography., May 29, 1843; 7 1/2" x 9 7/8"; Morton, Samuel George, 1799-1851
    6 pp. and endorsement. Com. Read by the author at the centenary celebration of 1843. See Pro., III, 115-118.
  - Letter to A. D. Bache, May 29, 1843; 7 15/16" x 9 7/8"; Norton, William A. (William Augustus), 1810-1883
    Philadelphia, 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Is under necessity of leaving Philadelphia before conclusion of the hundredth anniversary meeting of the A.P.S.
  - On fossil arborescent ferns of the family of Sigillaria., May 29, 1843; 7 13/16" x 9 15/16"; Taylor, Richard C. (Richard Cowling), 1789-1851
    1 p. and endorsement. Com. Read by the author at the centenary celebration of 1843. See Pro., III, 149-150.
  - On a new method of determining the velocity of projectiles., May 29, [1843]; 7 3/4" x 9 7/8"; Henry, Joseph, 1797-1878
    4 pp. and endorsement. Com. Read by the author at the centenary celebration of 1843. See Pro., III, 165-167.
  - Coprolites., May 29, [1843]; 8 1/16" x 12 3/8"; Lea, Isaac, 1792-1886
    2 pp. and endorsement. Com. Summary of oral communication presented at the centenary celebration of 1843. See Pro., III, 143.
  - Notice respecting the appearance of watersprouts on the Bahama banks, May 29, 1843; Taylor, Richard C. (Richard Cowling), 1789-1851
  - ---- and [Joseph] Henry., May 30, 1843; 7 5/8" x 12 1/2"; Goddard, Paul B. (Paul Beck), 1811-1866
    Photography. 2 pp. and endorsement. Com. Communication presented by the author at the centenary celebration of 1843. See Pro., III, 179-181.
  - Sketch of the history, theory, and practical results of the turbine of Fourneyron., May 30, 1843; 7 5/8" x 12 1/2"; Morris, Ellwood, 1813?-1872
    9 pp. and endorsement. Pp. numbered 1 to 13 but pp. 5-6 and 8-9 are missing. Com. Oral communication made by Mr. Morris at the centenary celebration of 1843. See Pro., III, 169-173.
  - Geological notices., May 30, 1843; 7 3/4" x 12 1/4"; Rogers, Henry D. (Henry Darwin), 1808-1866
    3 pp. and endorsement. Com. Oral communication presented before the centenary celebration of 1843. See Pro., III, 181-183.
  - Remarks upon cyanosis neonatorum, May 30, 1843; 7 7/8" x 9 13/16"; Meigs, Charles D. (Charles Delucena), 1792-1869
    and upon a new and more successful mode of cure. 5 pp. and endorsement. A.Com.S. Communication presented by the author at the centenary celebration of 1843. See Pro., III, 174-175.
  - On the instruments and astronomical observatory of the U. S. Military Academy, May 30, 1843; 7 7/8" x 9 3/4"; Bartlett, W. H. C. (William Holms Chambers), 1804-1893
    West Point, and the observations made upon the comet of 3pp. and endorsement. Paper incomplete. Com. Read by Professor Kendall at the centenary celebration of 1843. See Pro., III, 151-153.
  - The geology of Maryland., May 30, [1843]; 8 1/8" x 10 1/2"; Ducatel, Julius Timoleon, 1796-1849
    3 pp. and endorsement. Com. Summary of communication submitted in connection with centenary celebration of 1843. See Pro., III, 157-158.
  - Memoir on the geology of the northeast park of the island of Cuba., May 30, 1843; 7 13/16" x 9 15/16"; Taylor, Richard C. (Richard Cowling), 1789-1851
    2 pp. and endorsement. Com. Read by the author at the centenary celebration of 1843. See Pro., III, 154-155.
  - On the law of cooling of atmospheric air for various suddenly diminished pressures., May 30, [1843]; 7 5/8" x 12 3/8"; Espy, James P. (James Pollard), 1785-1860
    1 p. and endorsement. Com. Summary of communication read by Mr. Booth at the centenary celebration of 1843. See Pro., III, 155-157.
  - On the law of cooling of atmospheric air for various sudden diminished pressures., May 30, [1843]; 8" x 13"; Espy, James P. (James Pollard), 1785-1860
    5 pp. and endorsement. Com. Communication read by Mr. Booth at the centenary celebration of 1843. See Pro., III, 155-157.
  - Account of observations made at Philadelphia and Toronto, during the magnetic disturbance of May 6, 1843, Bache, A.D., (Alexander Dallas), 1806-1867
  - Report of committee on arrangements for the Centennial celebration., May, 1843; 10x7-1/2; American Philosophical Society
    D.S.: N. Chapman, J.K.Kane, Robley Dunglison, John Ludlow, F.Fraley, A.D.Bache, Geo.W.Smith. 7p. and end. Incomplete. Mentions B.Franklin. See APS Proc., II, 273. FILM 54-62 FRAME93
  - Letter to John C. Warren, June 3, 1843; 7 7/8" x 9 3/4"; Bache, A. D. (Alexander Dallas), 1806-1867
    Philadelphia, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Sends Dr. Warren a program of the centennial celebration of the A.P.S.
  - Letter to George Ord, June 3, 1843; 7 1/2" x 9 1/8"; Vaughan, Petty, 1788-1854
    London, 2 pp., address and endorsement. Acknowledges receipt of letter of May 13. Concerning payments for books and customs duties thereon.
  - Letter to Peter S. DuPonceau, June 3, 1843; 8" x 9"; Baber, Ambrose
    U. S. Legation, Turin, 1 p. and endorsement. A.L.S. Forwards several pamphlets (not named) to the A.P.S.
  - Resolution, June 16, 1843; 8 1/8" x 12 1/2"; American Philosophical Society
    [Philadelphia], 1 p. and endorsement. A.D.S.: J[ohn] K. Kane. Resolution to deliver possession of the museum property to Mr. Isaac Brown Packer.
  - Resolutions of thanks to societies and others who took part in the centennial anniversary, June 16, 1843; 8 1/8" x 12 1/2"; American Philosophical Society
    [Philadelphia,]. 1p. and endorsement. D. Printed in Pro., III, 217-218.
  - Letter to George Ord, June 16, 1843; 7 7/16" x 9 1/8"; Vaughan, Petty, 1788-1854
    London, 1 p., address and endorsement. Details concerning publications forwarded to the A.P.S. Includes parcel from Professor Faraday.
  - Letter to George Ord, June 19, 1843; 7 1/2" x 9 1/8"; Vaughan, Petty, 1788-1854
    Treasurer of A.P.S., London, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Forwards books from Astronomical and Geographical societies, and the Altona journals to the A.P.S.
  - Receipt to the American philosophical society for transferring insurance policy to the Museum company, June 21, 1843; 4-1/2x8; Ord, George, 1781-1866
    A.D. 1p., receipted by [G.Ord], and end.
  - Letter to Robley Dunglison, June 22, 1843; 7 3/4" x 9 7/8"; Ludlow, John, 1793-1857
    Secretray of A.P.S., University of Pennsylvania, [Philadelphia], 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Thanks A.P.S. for resolution requesting a copy of the prayer offered at centenial celebration.
  - Letter to [Alexander Dallas] Bache, June 28, 1843; 7 7/8" x 9 7/8"; Espy, James P. (James Pollard), 1785-1860
    Washington, 1 p. and endorsement. A.L.S. Regarding a change to be made in his paper on the law of cooling of atmospheric air.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, June 29, 1843; 9-1/2x8; Royal Geographical Society (Great Britain)
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, June 29, 1843; 9-3/4x8; Zoological Society of London
  - Letter to E[lisha] K. Kane, July 3, 1843; 8" x 12 1/2"; Andrews, William Winthrop
    Malta, 1 p. and endorsement. A.L.S. Transmits a catalogue of the minerals he presented to the A.P.S. in 1837. See Pro. IV, 9, September 15, 1843.
  - Letter to George Ord, July 3, 1843; 7 1/2" x 9 1/8"; Vaughan, William, 1752-1850
    London, 1 p., address and endorsement. L.S. Acknowledges receipt of annual box of Transactions from A.P.S. to Royal Society. Suggests that a similar set be sent to Longmans and Company.
  - Letter to the American Philosophical society, Philadelphia, July 4, 1843; 10x7-3/4; Academy of Natural Sciences of Philadelphia
    A.L.S.: Walter R. Johnson. 1p.,end.and add. Thanks for Transactions.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, July 4, 1843; 8x5; London Electrical Society
    A.L.S.: Charles V. Walker. 1p.,end. Forwards publication.
  - Letter to G[eorge] Ord, Librarian of A.P.S., July 5, 1843; 8 3/4" x 10 3/4"; Ombrosi, James
    Florence, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. United States consul acknowledges the receipt of diploma of membership in the A.P.S. sent to the Grand Duke of Florence, and has delivered the same.
  - Letter to G[eorge] Ord, July 14, 1843; 8 1/2" x 10 3/4"; Sartori, John B.
    Librarian of A.P.S., Leghorn, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.P.S. Acknowledges letter of April 7, together with several packages from the A.P.S., which he has forwarded as directed.
  - Letter to George Ord, Librarian of A.P.S., July 15, 1843; 8" x 10"; Crabb, H. N.
    Washington, 2 pp., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Concerning package to be forwarded to the Baron Van der Starten in New York.
  - Letter to the Secretary of the A.P.S., July 20, 1843; 7 1/4"x9"; Aspinwall, Thomas, 1786-1876
    Consulate of the U.S., London, 1p., address and endorsement. Forwards to the A.P.S.: five parcels from the London Electrical Society.
  - Report of committee on Parker's claim to the museum property, July 21, 1843; 10x8; American Philosophical Society
    [Philadelphia] D.S.: F. Fraley. 1p. and end.
  - Letter to Peter S. DuPonceau, July 24, 1843; 8 1/4" x 10 5/8"; de Santangelo, Orazio de Attellis. Ls-1
    President of the A.P.S., New York, 1 p., address and endorsements. A.L.S. Transmits to the A.P.S.: a donation from Don Paolo Anania de Luca, on acoustics. See Pro., IV, 6.
  - Letter to George Ord, August 4, 1843; 7 1/2" x 9 1/8"; Vaughan, Petty, 1788-1854
    London, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Has "written to Sir Wm. Jardine & the other Editors you name, proposing an exchange."
  - Letter to Geo[rge] Ord, August 7, 1843; 7 3/8" x 9 1/8"; Vaughan, Petty, 1788-1854
    London, 1 p. A.L.S. Forwards parcel containing items for George Ord, Isaac Lea, and the A.P.S.
  - Letter to George Ord, August 12, 1843; 6 1/8" x 8"; Du Ponceau, Peter Stephen, 1760-1844
    [Philadelphia], 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Concerning a package from England for the A.P.S., held at the post office.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, Aug. 15, 1843; 13x7-3/4; Deutsche Akademie der Wissenschaften zu Berlin
    Berlin, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Ehrenberg. 1p.,end. In German. Thanks for Proceedings and Transactions.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Aug. 15, 1843; 13x7-3/4; Deutsche Akademie der Wissenschaften zu Berlin
    Berlin, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Ehrenberg. 1p.,end. In German. Forwards publications.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, Aug. 17, 1843; 11x8-1/2; Akademie der Wissenschaften in Göttingen
    Göttingen, A.L.S.: J.Fr.L.Hausmann. 1p.,end.and add. Thanks for Transactions and Proceedings
  - Letter to George Ord, [Philadelphia], August 19, 1843; 5" x 7 15/16"; Littell, John S. (John Stockton), 1806-1875
    1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Complains of delay in payment for Silliman's journal.
  - Letter to G[eorge] Ord, September 7, 1843; 8 1/4" x 10 3/4"; Bossange, Edouard
    Librarian of A.P.S., New York, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Has just received, by boat from Havre, two trunks belonging to the late Genl. Fenwick. Asks instructions by return post.
  - Letter to George Ord, September 7, 1843; 7 1/2" x 9 1/8"; Vaughan, Petty, 1788-1854
    London, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Is forwarding a parcel containing "various collections of pamphlets." Sir William Jardine intends to send a set of his works.
  - Report of committee on Isaac Lea's paper: "Descriptions of new freshwater and land shells", Sept. 11, 1843; 10x8; American Philosophical Society
    [Philadelphia] D.S.: T. R. Peale, Isaac Hays and G. Ord. 1p., end.
  - Letter to [George] Ord, Sept. 12, 1843; 13x8-1/2; Académie royale des sciences, des lettres et des beaux-arts de Belgique
    Brussels, Printed D.filled in in ms.S.: Quetelet. 1p.,end. In French. Thanks for Transactions and Proceedings Concerning items lacking in APS.library.
  - Letter to George Ord, September 13, 1843; 7 5/8" x 10"; Armstrong, Edward
    Philadelphia, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Requests that C. G. Childs be allowed to borrow the portrait of "Penn at the age of 20."
  - Letter to G[eorge] Ord, September 15, 1843; 8 3/8" x 10 5/8"; Bossange, Edouard
    New York, 2 pp., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Bill of charges on imported package. Is empowered to receive all amounts due to his father.
  - Letter to [George Ord?], September 16, 1843; 7 1/2" x 9 1/8"; Vaughan, William, 1752-1850
    London, 2 pp. L.S. Concerning missing number of Royal Society Transactions, 1841, pt. 2. Return of Captain [Sir James Clark] Ross after an absence of four years.
  - Letter to Geo[rge] Ord, September 18, 1843; 7 3/4" x 9 7/8"; Patterson, Robert M. (Robert Maskell), 1787-1854
    Librarian of A.P.S., [Philadelphia], 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Introducing Professor Smith, of Brunswick, Maine, who wishes to visit the A.P.S. rooms.
  - Letter to George Ord, September 18, 1843; 7 1/2" x 9 1/8"; Vaughan, Petty, 1788-1854
    London, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Will send [William] Yarrell's third volume (upon birds) in next parcel. William Vaughan has replied concerning missing number of Royal Society Transactions.
  - Letter to Franklin Bache, September 19, 1843; 7 7/8" x 9 7/8"; Masters, Markoe & Co.
    New York, 1 p., address and endorsement. L.Signed: Masters Markoe & Co. Ask instructions as to box addressed to A.P.S. in New York custom house.
  - Letter to Messrs. Adams, Sept. 20, 1843; 8x5; Ord, George, 1781-1866
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p.and end. Instructions concerning a box for the society.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, Sept. 25, 1843; 10-3/4x8-1/4; Académie des sciences (France)
    Paris, Printed L.filled in in ms. S.: F.Arago.; 1p.,end.and add. In French. Thanks for Transactions and Proceedings.
  - Letter to George Ord, September 28, 1843; 8 1/2" x 10 3/4"; McCartee, B.
    Librarian of A.P.S., New York, 1p. address and endorsement A.L.S. Sails on the Huntress, October 4, for China. Will be glad to take papers for [Karl F.A.] Gutzlaff and [Robert] Morrison.
  - Letter to the Secretary of the A.P.S., September 28, 1843; 8 3/8" x 10 1/2"; Moskovskoe obshchestvo li︠u︡biteleĭ prirody
    Moscow, 1 p. and endorsement. D. (In French.) Forwards to the A.P.S.:publications listed herein.
  - Letter to J[oshua] F[rancis] Fisher, October 4, 1843; 5 5/8" x 9"; Haldeman, Samuel Steman, 1812-1880
    Chicquesalunga, near Columbia, Pa., 1p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Presents the sixth number of his work on freshwater univalve shells.
  - Report of committee on paper by H. C. Lea, "Description of some new fossil shells", Oct. 6, 1843; 6-1/2x7-1/2; American Philosophical Society
    Philadelphia, D.S.: Jas. C. Booth and Isaac Hays. 1p., end. See APS Proc., IV, 16.
  - Report of committee on expediency of preparing report on scientific labors of the APS, Oct. 6, 1843; 10x7-1/2; American Philosophical Society
    [Philadelphia], D.S.: John Ludlow, A. D. Bache, Geo. W. Smith, and Henry D. Rogers. 3p. and end. See APS Proc., IV, 16.
  - Letter to [George] Ord, October 6, 1843; 7 7/8" x 9 7/8"; Hare, Robert
    Philadelphia, 2 pp. and endorsement. A.L.S. Encloses catalogue of the library of Brown University for the A.P.S.
  - Letter to Geo[rge] Ord, October 7, 1843; 7 15/16" x 10"; Vaughan, Petty, 1788-1854
    London, 1 p., address and endorsement. Forwards [William] Yarrell's three volumes (upon birds), the Altona journals, and a parcel for Professor Bache.
  - Report of committee on paper by Elias Loomis "On two storms...in the month of February 1842", Oct. 13, 1843; 9x8; American Philosophical Society
    [Philadelphia] D.S.: John F. Frazer and A. D. Bache. 1p., end. See APS Proc.., IV, 17. Printed: APS Trans., n.s., IX, 161-184.
  - Resolutions regarding preparation of a report on the scientific labors of the APS, Oct. 13, 1843; 8x6; Kane, John K. (John Kintzing), 1795-1858
    [Philadelphia] D. 2p.and add. to Rev. John Ludlow. See APS Proceedings, IV, 17-18.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, Oct. 17, 1843; 10x8; Brown University
    Providence, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: F.Wayland, Pres.and Robinson Potter Dunn, Asst.Libn. 1p., end.and add. Thanks for Proceedings.
  - Letter to the American Philosophical society, Philadelphia, Oct. 18, 1843; 10x8; Harvard University
    Cambridge, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Josiah Quincy, Pres.and Thaddeus William Harris, Librarian. 1p.end and add.: Care of P.S.Duponceau. Thanks for publications.
  - Report of committee on paper by [W.H.C.] Bartlett on the West Point observatory, Oct. 19, 1843; 6x8; American Philosophical Society
    [Philadelphia] D. S.: Sears C. Walker, A. D. Bache, and E. Otis Kendall. 1P. See APS Proceedings, IV, 19. Printed: APS Transactions, n.s., IX, 191-203.
  - Report of committee on paper by Jas. D. Booth and Martin Boye "On the conversion of benzoic into hippuric acid", Oct. 20, 1843; 10x8; American Philosophical Society
    Hall of the Philosophical Society, D.S.: John F. Frazer, A. D. Bache, and Rob't Hare. 1p., end. See APS Proc., IV, 20. Printed: APS Trans., IX, 185-190.
  - Report of committee on paper by S. G. Morton on "The form of the head...of the ancient Egyptians.", Oct. 20, 1843; 10x8; American Philosophical Society
    [Philadelphia] D.S.: R. M. Patterson, Robley Dunglison and Paul B. Goddard. 1p.,end. See APS Proc., IV, 22. Printed: APS Trans., n.s., IX, 93-159 andplates.
  - Report of committee on two papers by Richard G. Taylor, Oct. 20, 1843; 10x8; American Philosophical Society
    [Philadelphia], D.S.: John F. Frazer and A. D. Bache. 1p., end. See APS Proc., IV, 19-20.
  - Letter to Geo[rge] Ord, October 27, 1843; 7 3/4" x 9 7/8"; Patterson, Robert M. (Robert Maskell), 1787-1854
    [Philadelphia], 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Inquires about diploma of membership in the A.P.S. for [Stephen] Endlicher of Vienna.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, Oct. 28, 1843; 10x8; Bowditch Library
    A.L.S.: H.I.Bowditch. 1p.,end.and add. Thanks for Proceedings.
  - Letter to George Ord, October 28, 1843; 7 3/4" x 9 7/8"; Patterson, Robert M. (Robert Maskell), 1787-1854
    [Philadelphia], 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Regarding diploma of membership in the A.P.S. for [Stephen] Endlicher.
  - Letter to the Am[erican] Philo[sophical] Society, October, 1843; 8" x 10"; Upshur, A. P. (Abel Parker), 1790-1844
    Department of State, [Washington, D.C.], 1 p. and endorsement. D.S. Sends to the A.P.S.: documents of 27 Congress, 2 session.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Nov. 2, 1843; 15x9-1/2; Geological Society of London
    Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Robert W. Austen. 1p.,end.: R.D[unglison] and add: P.Vaughan. Thanks for Transactions and Proceedings
  - Letter to John K. Kane, Secretary of A.P.S., November 2, 1843; 8" x 10"; Hopkinson, Francis, 1781-1870
    Philadelphia, 1 p. and endorsement. A.L.S. Presents an engraving of [Thomas] Sully's portrait of his father to A.P.S.
  - Report of committee on Mr. Kane's resolutions, Nov. 3, 1843; 10x8; American Philosophical Society
    [Philadelphia] D.S.: John Ludlow, A. D. Bache. Geo. W. Smith, and Joseph Henry. 1p. and end.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Nov. 3, 1843; 9-1/4x7-1/2; Royal Society of Arts (Great Britain)
    L.S.: Francis Whishaw. 1p.,end.: R.D[unglison]. Thanks for Transactions.
  - Letter to Geo(rge) Ord, November 3, 1843; 8" x 10"; Vaughan, Petty, 1788-1854
    London, 2 pp., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Acknowledges receipt of letters of September 25 and 27 and October 13. Book news.
  - Letter to George Ord, November 7, 1843; 7 7/8" x 9 15/16"; Vaughan, Petty, 1788-1854
    London, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Has forwarded works of Sir William Jardine to the A.P.S. via the Susquehanna.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, Nov. 9, 1843; 10-1/4x8; Muséum national d'histoire naturelle (France)
    Paris, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: E.Chevreul, Milne-Edwards and Cordier. 1p.,end. In French. Thanks for Transactions and Proceedings.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, Nov. 11, 1843; 10x8; Royal Asiatic Society of Great Britain and Ireland
    London, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: R.Clarke. 1p.,end. Thanks for Transactions and Proceedings
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Nov. 13, 1843; 10-3/4x8-1/4; Académie des sciences (France)
    Paris, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: F.Arago. 1p.,end. In French. Thanks for Proceedings.
  - Letter to George Ord, November 16, 1843; 4 15/16" x 7 5/8"; Bache, A. D. (Alexander Dallas), 1806-1867
    [Philadelphia], 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Introducing Mr. Garnett Adrain, of New Brunswick, who wishes to examine his father's contributions to the A.P.S. Transactions.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, Nov. 17, 1843; 10x8; Society of Antiquaries of London
    Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Nicholas Carlisle. 1p.,end.and add. Thanks for Proceedings and Transactions
  - Letter to George Ord, November 18, 1843; 7 3/4'' x 9 3/4''; Henry, Joseph, 1797-1878
    Librarian of A.P.S., Princeton, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Requests loan of ''last vol. of the scientific memoirs.'' FILM 235 FRAME 18
  - Letter to Geo[rge] Ord, November 22, 1843; 7 3/4" x 9 7/8"; Patterson, Robert M. (Robert Maskell), 1787-1854
    Librarian of A.P.S., [Philadelphia], 1 p. and endorsement. A.L.S. Arrangements for the funeral of F.R. Hassler.
  - Letter to Geo[rge] Ord, November 25, 1843; 7 3/8" x 8 7/8"; Newman, Edward, 1801-1876
    L-9 Librarian of the A.P.S., London, 1 p., address and endorsements. A.L.S. Presents to the A.P.S.: a copy of his essay, System of Nature. See Pro., IV, 42.
  - Statement of account with the American philosophical society, Nov. 30, 1843; 10-1/2x8-1/2; Bossange, Hector, 1795-1884
    Paris, D. 1p.,end. by George Ord,and end. In French.
  - Letter to Geo[rge] Ord, December 4, 1843; 7 15/16" x 10"; Vaughan, William, 1752-1850
    London, 1 p., address and endorsement. L.S. Has forwarded parcel from Royal Society to the the A.P.S. in a box addressed to Mr. J. C. Cresson.
  - ---- Wheelwright to the President of the American Institution for the Promotion of Science, December 4, 1843; 8 3/4" x 10 7/8"; Wheelwright, William, 1798-1873
    London, 1 p. and endorsement. L. in 3d. per. Presents a copy of his report on Steam Navigation in the Pacific.
  - Letter to George Ord, December 6, 1843; 7 7/16" x 9 1/8"; Vaughan, William, 1752-1850
    London, 2 pp., address and endorsement. L.S. Acknowledges receipt of account of hundredth anniversary of A.P.S.; no. 26 of Proceedings; and diploma for Rev. George Peacock.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, Dec. 9, 1843; 9x7; Royal Asiatic Society of Great Britain and Ireland
  - Letter to George Ord, December 11, 1843; 6 3/16" x7 7/8"; Bache, A. D. (Alexander Dallas), 1806-1867
    [Philadelphia], Librarian of A.P.S., 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Introducing Professor Richard S. McCulloch, who "wishes to look over our Bulletin."
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Dec. 14, 1843; 15x9; Geological Society of London
    Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: William J. Hamilton. 1p.,end.and add.: P.Vaughan, Esq. Thanks for Proceedings.